

alexjmold.com alexjmold@gmail.com 07508336039

PROFILE

Committed and ambitious individual that enjoys creating beautifully interactive experiences for the web. Since graduating from Goldsmiths with First Class Honours in (BSc) Creative Computing I've had the opportunity to work on a wide variety of projects in both scale and range of technologies over the last 8 years in industry. I'm naturally passionate about problem solving by creating new solutions. I am able to grasp new concepts quickly and work efficiently under pressure.

EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Engineer / CTO at HelpMeChoose.ai 2021 - 2024

- Created the entire SaaS product from start to finish using modern web technologies.
- Managed different teams of developers to meet deadlines and meet the needs of both the product design and customer service teams.
- Kept the SaaS product up to date with the newest technologies such as A.I integrations to improve overall customer satisfaction.
- Upgraded the initial platform substantially to encompass a larger user base and different deployment platforms such as the Shopify App.
- Reached up to 36x higher sales conversions, 30x higher basket values and 45% higher customer satisfaction on e-commerce sites using the platform.

Front-End Developer at StratumFive 2019 - 2021

- Made significant contributions to a range of apps produced for the Maritime sector.
- Utilised features such as offline synchronisation with progressive web applications (Vue.js + TypeScript).
- UX/UI design for many new features that had a real world impact.
- Managed communications between stake-holders and the backend team to implement new features.

Creative Technologist at Kitty 2017 - 2019

- Involved in prototyping new applications with quick deadlines ranging from interactive articles and data visualisations, to full scale e-commerce solutions that spanned multiple international markets.
- Researched and created projects with emerging technologies such as voice search and visualisation frameworks.

 Managed the development workflow of the team to meet deadlines in a fast paced agency environment.

Developer at ROAST 2016 - 2017

- Worked closely with the campaigns team to build bespoke interactive projects for events and content-led campaign work.
- Created data visualisations and full website builds for a range of clients.
- Increased productivity output of the team by creating developer frameworks to ship interactive pieces faster.

Junior Developer at Mode Digital 2015 - 2016

- Built tailor-made websites that aligned with the campaign strategies of the rest of the team.
- Was part of a team that created a range of websites for companies including e-commerce solutions as well as bespoke content focused websites.

EDUCATION

Goldsmiths, University of London

First Class Honours (BSc) Creative Computing, 2016.

Weymouth College

(BTEC) Interactive Media Production (Distinction, Distinction, Distinction*), 2012.

SKILLS

- · HTML/CSS (SCSS)
- JavaScript (TypeScript, Vue.js, Nuxt.js, React.js, Next.js, Node.js, Express.js)
- PostgreSQL
- Supabase
- Clickhouse
- Astro
- WordPress
- · Webpack / Vite
- · AWS
- · Digital Ocean
- OpenAl
- Github / GitLab
- · CI/CD
- Sketch
- Figma